Preliminary Guide to the The Harold Washington Library Center Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harold Washington Library Center collection
1988-1988
MS 1493
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.75
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of submission proposals and technical specifications from the five architectural firms that participated in the Harold Washington Library Center competition in Chicago in 1988. Also included are public comments and records of the Technical Review Committee.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Thomas Beeby, 1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The Harold Washington Library Center, Chicago Public Library's central building, is designed in the neo-classical style, using elements of both ancient Greek and Roman architecture. It was designed by Thomas Beeby, of the firm Hammond, Beeby and Babka, who won the 1998 competition conducted by the library. At the time of its opening, on October 7, 1991, the Harold Washington Library Center was the largest public library in the world, at 756,640 square feet.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of submission proposals and technical specifications from the five architectural firms that participated in the Harold Washington Library Center competition in Chicago in 1988. Also included are public comments and records of the Technical Review Committee.
Architecture -- Designs and plans; Library architecture; Library buildings; Harold Washington Library Center (Chicago Public Library)
- Inventory
  - The Buck Turner Association (formerly The John Buck Company): submission proposal, technical specifications and narrative, 1988 May (Box 1)
  - Metropolitan Structures Limited Partnership (formerly Metropolitan/Lohan): submission proposal, 1988 May (Box 1)
  - Library '88 Partnership: submission proposals and technical specifications [vols. I-II and appendix], 1988 May (Box 2)
  - The Chicago Library Team, Inc. (formerly Paschen-Tishman-Jahn): Design/Build proposal (4 vols.), 1988 May (Box 3)
  - The SEBUS Group: submission proposals and technical specifications
    General note
    See: Box 5
  - Public comments, 1988 May 15-19 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Energy system evaluations, 1988 June (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Technical Review Team requests for clarification
    - The Buck-Turner Association, 1988 May (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Metropolitan Structures, Ltd., 1988 May (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Library '88 Partnership, 1988 May (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The SEBUS Group, 1988 May (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Chicago Library Team, Inc., 1988 May (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Technical Review Committee Report (4 vols.), 1988 (Box 4)
  - Video review of finalists in the Design/Build competition, 1988 June (Box 4A)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - The SEBUS Group: submission proposals and technical specifications, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Drawings
    - The Buck-Turner Association, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Metropolitan Structures, Ltd., 1988 (Box 6)
    - Library '88 Partnership, 1988 (Box 6)
    - The SEBUS Group, 1988 (Box 6)
    - The Chicago Library Team, Inc., 1988 (Box 7)